WESLEY CHUN: 我是Wesley Chun
WESLEY CHUN: This is Wesley Chun.
在Google我们希望我们的工具
Here at Google, we want our tools
能够帮助你建立出下一个杀手级应用程序
enable you to build the next killer app.
在这期Dev Byte  我会给你介绍
In this Dev Byte, I'll introduce you
Google云平台的核心部件
to the core components of the Google Cloud Platform.
我也会分享其他人在使用它时的一些
I'll also share a few stories of what others have already
小故事
done with it.
一旦你熟悉了这个平台的服务
Once you're familiar with the services in the platform,
你也会被Google的丰富资源  经验和性能所影响
you too will be able to leverage Google's vast resources,
来帮助你强大你的好点子
experience, and performance to help you power that great idea.
在Google  我们总是在考虑规模和创新
At Google, we're always thinking about scale and innovation.
这是一些研究论文
Here are some of the research papers
多年来我们发表的
we published over the years, many of which
其中许多论文直接导致了Google云平台的服务
have led directly to services in the Google Cloud Platform.
你已经知道Google Search  YouTube和Gmail服务
You already know Google Search and YouTube and Gmail services
他们已经在Google大规模的运行
which run at Google scale.
如果你可以利用这些服务之后的这种规模和创新
What if you could take advantage of that kind of scale
来为你的伟大想法提供帮助呢
and innovation that's behind our services, but for your big idea?
这就是Google云平台的价值所在
This is where the Google Cloud Platform steps in,
让你的应用得到Google的力量
enabling you to take your app to the power of Google.
那什么是Google云平台呢
What is the Google Cloud Platform?
简单的说  它是一个服务的集合
Well, in brief, it's a collection
这些服务由三个类别组成  计算  存储
of services organized into three categories-- compute, storage,
和应用程序  以帮助你的应用规模化运行
and application services to help your apps scale.
选择你想要的服务
Pick and choose which services you want,
而只需为你使用的资源付款
and only pay for the resources you use.
我们从计算类别开始
We begin with the compute category,
我们已经有了Google App引擎和Google Compute引擎
where we've got Google App Engine and Google Compute Engine.
让我们从Compute引擎开始  我们在基础设施里
Let's start with Compute Engine, our computing solution
的计算方案即服务层
at the infrastructure as a service layer.
创建Linux虚拟机并且连接到它们
Create Linux virtual machines and connect to them
就像其他网络计算机一样
like any other network computer.
它们的特点是拍摄持久磁盘快照  虚拟机在线迁移
They feature persistent disks with snapshotting, live virtual
以避免烦人的维护周期
machine migration to get around those pesky maintenance
网络连接和防火墙  负载均衡
periods, networking and firewalls, load balancing,
以及为高可用设计的地域分区
and regional zones for high availability
以实现你的技术栈并且解决真正的大问题
to implement your technology stack and solve really big problems with.
有多大呢
How big?
恩，这里有一个真正的大数据例子
Well, here's an example of really big data.
比如说你要打算结婚了
Let's say you were going to get married
你想要一个盛大的婚礼  需要准备邀请你
and you wanted a huge wedding and needed prepare invitations
最亲密的150亿位朋友和亲戚
for your closest 15 billion friends
他们中有大概70亿来自地球
and relatives, which is roughly 7 billion guests from Earth
其他人来自其他星球
and the other eight from other planets.
不管怎样  我们只能说我们有
Well, anyway, let's just say we had that
你组织的地点  大约
and you were organizing the addresses, roughly about
每个100字节的信封
100 bytes each, for the envelopes.
为了确认这里面没有任何重复
But to make sure there aren't any duplicates,
你需要将所有数据排序
you would need to sort all of that data.
正好  MapR团队去年做了一些相同的工作
Well, the MapR did something similar last year
在Compute引擎中使用Hadoop去设置分钟排序记录
using Hadoop on Compute Engine to set the minute sort record.
他们的app能够获取150亿个100字节大小的记录
Their app was able to take 15 billion 100 byte directors,
也就是1.5TB  或1500GB的数据
meaning 1.5 terabytes, or 1,500 gigs of data,
并在不到一分钟的时间内进行排序
and sorted it all in less than a minute.
在此之上  它们可以重现这个结果
On top of this, they were able to reproduce this result
持续跨多节点运行不同的集群配置
consistently across multiple runs and different cluster
configurations.
点击这个链接获得更多细节
Click the link for more details.
另一个计算解决方案是App引擎
The other Compute solution is App Engine,
我们的平台作为一个服务提供方
our platform as a service offering.
这个方案提供给不想管理这方面事情和
This solution is for developers who want to be more hands off
不希望解决这么多系统管理问题的开发者
and don't want to deal that much with system administration.
因此在硬件和你的app之间的组件
So components living between the hardware and your app,
例如操作系统  数据库和Web服务器
such as the operating system, the database, and web servers,
都是由Google进行托管  因此你可以专注与自己的应用程序
are all managed by Google so you can focus on your app.
使用熟悉的语言来构建你的解决方案
Build your solution using familiar languages
像Java  Python  PHP和Go
like Java, Python, PHP, and Go.
上传你的代码并且让Google照顾这一切
Upload your code and let Google take care of everything else.
Snapchat是一个十分流行的照片分享服务
Snapchat is a highly popular photo sharing service
它一天服务超过3.5亿张照片和快照
which serves more than 350 million photos or snaps a day.
是什么让他们发展到今天的规模
What got them to scale to where they are today?
是Google App引擎
Google App Engine.
Google云存储为你提供大型数据仓库
Google Cloud Storage is for your massive data repository.
存储大量的文件和几乎任何大小的blob格式数据
Store any number of files and blobs of virtually any size
对用户提供安全的控制访问
securely with controlled access to users,
以及应用程序和其他Google云平台的服务
as well as apps and other Google Cloud Platform services that
可以处理和分析你的数据
can process and analyze your data.
Song Pop是这一代的名字
Song Pop is this generation's name
这个曲调应用运行在Google App引擎上
that tune app running on Google App Engine.
伴随着Google云存储  他们的app
Along with Google Cloud Storage, their app
一天为8千万客户提供超过18TB的音乐
serves more than 18 terabytes a day of music to its 80 million users.
Google Cloud SQL是在云端完全托管的  高度可用的
Google Cloud SQL is the fully managed, highly available
关系数据库服务
relational database service in the cloud.
创造  配置和使用MySQL数据库
Create, configure, and use MySQL databases,
但是是在我们的数据中心承载它
but host it in our data centers.
标准的MySQL Wire协议
The standard MySQL wire protocol lets
让你从任何地方使用任何app连接上云端SQL
you connect to Cloud SQL from any app anywhere.
同时它也支持JDBC
And it also supports JDBC.
从复制  加密  补丁管理和备份中释放自己
Free yourself from replication, encryption, patch management,
以便你可以专注于你的解决方法
and backups so that you can focus on your solution.
它的一个最好的特点是它的
One of its best features is its pay
按使用付费模式  用户可以选择为一个数据库
per use model, where customers can opt to pay for a database
仅当它被使用时才支付费用  然后在剩下的时间
only when it's being used, and then for inexpensive storage
使用便宜的存储
the rest of the time.
Google云数据存储是存储
Google Cloud Data Store is the place
NoSQL的键值数据的地方
to store your NoSQL key value data.
它是一个完全托管的服务  可以自动的处理
It's a fully managed service which automatically handles
分片  复制和扩容
sharding, replication, and scaling.
存储的机制是非结构的和支持基于对象
The storage mechanism is schemeless and supports either
或者SQL-like的查询  与资产交易一样
object based or SQL-like queries as well as Asset transactions.
云数据库是同样的技术
Cloud Datastore is the same technology
支持App引擎本地数据存储
that powers App Engine's native data store.
Google BigQuery是一个令人兴奋地  大规模的数据分析工具
Google BigQuery is an exciting, massive data analysis
可以让你在数据集中做查询
tool that lets you make queries on data sets
之前是不可能的  困难的或是很消耗时间的
that were previously impossible, difficult, or significantly
这些数据集比如四十年前婴儿的名字
time consuming-- data sets such as baby names for the last four
每个字都用Shakespeare书写
decades, every word written by Shakespeare,
或者是1929年以来的全球历史气象站数据
or global historical weather station data since 1929.
使用BigQuery  你用SQL查询可以在几秒钟内
Using BigQuery, you can analyze terabytes of data
分析TB级别的数据
in mere seconds using SQL-like queries.
在BigQuery的交互式Web控制台中
Here in BigQuery's interactive web console,
你可以针对你的数据集做点对点的查询
you can issue ad hoc queries against your data set.
用今天讲的三个公共数据集其中的一个进行测试
Take it for a test drive with one of these free public data
例如我刚刚提到的那个
sets today, such as the ones I just mentioned
或者这个特别的查询
or this particular query, which lets
它可以使你推到五大最新的维基百科页面
you pull up the five top most updated Wikipedia pages.
Google Cloud Endpoints使你无缝的
Google Cloud Endpoints enables you to seamlessly
创建APIs或者应用端点到你的服务里
create APIs or application endpoints to your service,
让你更方便地添加新的Web或移动前端
allowing you to more easily add new web or mobile front
到你现有的服务
ends to your existing service.
它是你的应用前端客户端与
It's the glue between your app's front end
后台连接在一起的胶水
clients and your back end.
通过Google App引擎
Your web or mobile clients connect
你的网站或手机客户端可以连接到云端
to Cloud Endpoints via Google App Engine
这样你可以去后端服务
so that you can go back end services there or have
或者能满足这些需求的App引擎的概略代码
skeleton codes sitting on App Engine for those requests
给到你实际上的后端  无论它
to your actual back end, whether it
在计算引擎上还是其他外部服务器上
be on Compute Engine or other external servers.
安全可以通过数据授权自动地
Security via data authorization is automatically
在前端和App Engine之间完成
handled between the front ends and App Engine.
甚至还有一个工具可以生成客户端代码
There is even a tool that generates border plate client
Android使用Java  iOS使用Objective C
side code in Java for Android, Objective C for iOS,
通用网络访问使用JavaScript
and JavaScript for generic web access
来帮助你更加快速的进行
to help you get going even faster.
这就是Google云平台
So that's the Google Cloud Platform--
为其他人做了什么  最重要的是
what it's done for others and most importantly, what
它可以为你做什么
it can do for you.
我们期待在你下一个伟大的想法中帮到你
We look forward to helping you with your next big idea.